International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Zimmerman, Charles S. papers, 1919-1958 [bulk 1920-1945]. 5780/014
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Charles S. Zimmerman papers
1919-1958 [bulk 1920-1945].
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Zimmerman, Charles S., 1896-1983.
5780/014
25 cubic feet
25 linear ft.
Correspondence, reports, minutes, newspaper clippings, and broadsides.
The Charles Zimmerman papers consist primarily of correspondence, reports, minutes, newspaper clippings, and broadsides dealing with his activities as a leader in Local 22 (in Series I), as well as his other union and political activities (in Series II).
3654695
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Robert E. Lazar
Date completed:
January 1979
EAD encoding:
Casey S. Westerman, August 2, 2002
Biographical / Historical
Charles S. Zimmerman, labor leader, political activist, and officer, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU).
Charles Zimmerman was born in Russia in 1896 and emigrated to the U.S. in 1913. He worked in the New York garment industry and joined ILGWU Local 22; shortly thereafter, he became its secretary-manager. He was also an organizer for the Joint Board of the Dress and Waistmakers' Union. Throughout the 1920s, Zimmerman was an active member of the Communist Party, which affiliation cost him his union leadership positions in 1925. By 1931, however, he was reinstated in the ILGWU and was elected a vice-president in 1934.
1897 Born in Talne, Ukraine, Russia. Studied in Kheder and Talmud Torah.
1907 Entered local Russian secular school.
1913 Arrived in United States. Lived with relatives on Lower East Side.
1913-16 Worked in garment and non garment shops.
1913 Participated in a strike to form a union and joined Local 19, United Garment Workers, on Clinton Street.
1914 Mother and brother came from Europe and joined CSZ and his sister.
1913-17 Attended public night school and Manhattan Preparatory School.
1916 Joined Local 25, ILGWU, and factory went out on strike. Elected shop chairman.
1917 Joined Socialist Party.
1918 International Workers of the World (IWW).
1919 Conducted organizing drive for Local 9 in Long Branch, N.J. Hall chairman in organization strike of Local 25.
1930 Joined the United Cloak and Dressmakers Progressive League as member #1.
1931 Rejoined ILGWU.
1931 Formed Committee of 25 to rebuild Local 22.
1931 After rejoining Local 22, formed Progressive League (or Group).
1932 Elected to executive board of Local 22.
1933 Elected manager-secretary of Local 22.
1934 Elected to General Executive Board.
1940 Resigned from Lovestone group.
1945-46 Trip to Europe, visiting Poland, Sweden and Norway on behalf of Jewish Labor Committee.
1947 Elected chairman, Trade Union Council, Liberal Party. 1958 Elected general manager of Dress Joint Board.
1958 Served as worker delegate to Sixth Session of Textiles Committee of International Labour Organization.
1966 Helped found Inter-American Federation of Textile and Garment Workers.
1969 Training ship, "Charles S. Zimmerman," christened by Seafarers International Union.
1972 Resigned as Union vice president and general manager of Dress Joint Council and N.Y., Dress Joint Board.
Scope and Contents
The Charles Zimmerman papers consist primarily of correspondence, reports, minutes, newspaper clippings, and broadsides dealing with his activities as a leader in Local 22 (in Series I), as well as his other union and political activities (in Series II).
The remainder of the materials covers union affairs, both within and outside of the ILGWU, from the 1920s to the 1950s, as well as labor issues in general. There is a good deal of information on civil rights and African-American employees from the 1930s to the 1950s. Other subjects include anti-fascism and anti-Nazism; strikes and other labor disputes in the U.S. and Canada; union elections; and worker education.
Significant organizations represented in the Zimmerman collection include the AFL and CIO (before and after the merger); the Fur and Leather Workers' Union; the Jewish Labor Committee; joint boards and locals of the ILGWU, especially Local 22 in New York; the League for Industrial Democracy; the NAACP; the National Urban League; the Workmen's Circle; and the Works Progress Administration.
Notable individuals represented include: Luigi Antonini; Irving Brown; David Dubinsky, Julius Hochman; Fiorello LaGuardia; Tom Mooney; Rose Pesotta; Adam Clayton Powell; Jackie Robinson; Norman Thomas; and Roy Wilkins.
Among the most significant material in the collection is correspondence documenting Zimmerman's activities with the Communist Party in the U.S. and its various factions and splinter groups, as well as other political organizations and figures. Correspondents include Jay Lovestone and William Z. Foster; there is also considerable material dealing with the Communist Party of the U.S.A. and the "Majority Group," or Lovestone faction. Other political parties represented include the American Labor Party, the Liberal Party (New York State), and the Socialist Party.
Related Materials
5780/014 P. Charles S. Zimmerman. ILGWU Local 22. Dressmaker's Union. Photographs, 1910-1958.
5780/015. ILGWU Local 22. Dressmaker's Union. Papers, 1920-1933.
5780/036. ILGWU Local 22. Dressmakers' Union. Minutes, 1934-1972.
5780/057. ILGWU Local 22. Dressmaker's Union. Education Department records, 1933-1975, 1950-1970 (bulk).
5780/067. ILGWU Local 22. Dressmaker's Union. Israel Breslow. Manager's records.
5780/178. Charles Zimmerman, collector. Radical pamphlets.
5780 OH. ILGWU. Oral Histories.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by subject within each series.
Arrangement
I. Local 22. Subject files, 1933-1958.
Boxes 1-39
II. Subject files, 1919-1932.
Boxes 40-50
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
African Americans -- Employment; Anti-fascist movements.; Anti-Nazi movement.; Civil rights -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Communists -- United States; Communism -- United States; Labor disputes -- United States; Labor disputes -- Canada; Labor unions and communism -- United States; Labor unions -- Officials and employees; Labor union locals.; Strikes and lockouts--United States.; Strikes and lockouts -- Canada; Working class -- Education -- United States; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 20th century; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; Correspondence; Reports; Clippings; Minutes; Broadsides; Zimmerman, Charles S.,; Antonini, Luigi, 1883-1968.; Brown, Irving, 1911-; Dubinsky, David, 1892-; Foster, William Z., 1881-1961.; Hochman, Julius, 1892-1970.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Lovestone, Jay.; Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942.; Pesotta, Rose, 1896-; Powell, Adam Clayton, 1908-1972.; Robinson, Jackie, 1919-1972.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Wilkins, Roy, 1901-; Zimmerman, Charles S., 1896-1983.; AFL-CIO; American Federation of Labor; American Jewish Congress; Communist Party of the U.S.A. (Majority Group); Communist Party of the United States of America; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.); International Fur and Leather Workers Union of the United States and Canada; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.--Management.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 22 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 22 (New York, N.Y.). Management; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); League for Industrial Democracy; Liberal Party of New York State; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; National Urban League; Socialist Party (U.S.); United States. Works Progress Administration; Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring
3654695
- I. Local 22. Subject files, 1933-1958.
  - A: 1935-57. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abrams, Jacob: 1951-53. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Affairs of Local 22: 1936-37. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agreements: 1929-57. Includes memoranda reached in conference between Affiliated Dress Manufacturers' Association, Inc., and Joint Board of Cloak, Dress and Fur Workers Union of the Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union; agreement between Dress Manufacturers Protective Association, Inc. and Joint Board, etc., 1929; independent agreements. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born: 1936-44. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Americans for Democratic Action: 1957-58. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Labor: 1933-June 1936. Includes William Green letter criticizing C.S. Zimmerman for supporting "sympathetic" strike in San Francisco and Zimmerman reply, Aug. 1934; other documents refer to AFL-CIO controversy. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AFL: July 1936-Dec. 1936. Includes survey by Isadore Polier on the legal problems involved in the suspension and expulsion of AFL unions, copies of correspondence between William Green, David Dubinsky and John L. Lewis on AFL-CIO controversy. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AFL (-CIO, Post-1955): 1937-58. Includes documents on AFL-CIO controversy. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AFL-CIO Committees: 1957. Includes AFL-CIO Ethical Practices Committee report on Teamsters Union. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - AFL, CIO, World War II Effort: 1942-44. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Jewish Congress: 1939-50. Includes correspondence re study of the dress industry by the Commission on the Economic Problems of the AJC, 1939. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Labor Party: 1935-45. Includes CSZ letter to David Dubinsky protesting method of taxation and functioning of organization, June 1938; newspaper clippings. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Labor Party, Ladies' Garment Centers 1948-50. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Youth Congress: 1935-37. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Amun-Israeli Housing Corp.: 1949-Mar. 1950. Includes correspondence, reports, minutes, legal matters. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Amun-Israeli Housing Corp.: Mar. 1950-May 1950. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Amun-Israeli Housing Corp: June 1950-Dec. 1950. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Amun-Israeli Housing Corp.: 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Amun-Israeli Housing Corp.: 1952-57. 1963-67. Includes correspondence with Israel Breslow. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Andrews, Sarainne Lowe: 1935-41. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Semitism, USA: 1930s. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ANTIFA (Palestinian League Against War and Fascism and for Jewish-Arab Solidarity): 1937. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Appeal Committee Reports to Executive Board, Local 22: 1934-46. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - B: 1936-57, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica: 1938, 1940. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Banks: 1933-47. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Birobidjan, Jewish Colonization in the Soviet Union: 1936-48. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Birthday, CSZ 50th: 1947. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Birthday, CSZ 60th: 1957. (Box 3, Folder 0.1)
  - Broadcasts, Local 22: 1939. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brookwood Labor College: 1935-36. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bund Archives: 1951-58. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Business Agents: 1940's. Includes lists of shops. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - C: 1936-52. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Canadian Area, Montreal: 1925, 1932-50. Julius Hochman letter to employers to create machinery for the adjustments of disputes, 1925; correspondence with Bernard Shane, printed material, newspaper clippings. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Area, Montreal: 1934-35. Frank Breslow correspondence; includes correspondence re Breslow jailed for strike activities; correspondents includes Kalmen Kaplansky, Bernard Shane. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Canadian Area, Toronto: 1934-49. Includes correspondence with Harry Langer and Laible Hoffmitz on Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union of Canada; printed material and newspaper clippings. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Catholic Interracial Council: 1950-57. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Central Trades and Labor Council: 1934-57. Includes CSZ letter to James C. Quinn (secretary) criticizing Council's unseating of Local 22 as an affiliate of the Central Trades, June 1937. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Citations: 1945-55. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Civil Rights Organizations: 1935-48. Includes Committee for the Defense of Civil Rights in Tampa, Civil Rights Defense Committee. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Civil Rights Organizations: 1949-56. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Civil Rights Committees and Conferences: 1957. Includes Civil Rights Committee of the AFL-CIO (CSZ member). (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights Committee, AFL-CIO: 1958-Jan. 1961. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Communism and Communists: 1933-41. Correspondence with individuals, groups and organizations. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Communism and Communists: 1942-46. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Communism and Communists: 1947-57. Includes case of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg and Morton Sobel, 1953-57. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Communism, Trade Unions: 1934-56. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Community Chests: 1941, 1947-56. Labor's participation and Councils of America, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Complaints from Union Members: 1935-55. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations: 1935-36. Includes correspondence re AFL, CIO controversy; CIO organizing activities. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - CIO: 1937-47. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Congress of Racial Equality: 1954-58. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Congressional and Senatorial Letters: 1948-55. Includes replies re bills before House and Senate. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Contractors, Employers: 1930's. Includes United Association News, Oct. and Nov. 1937. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Conventions, ILGWU: 1932-34. Includes reports and resolutions, submitted by Local 22 delegates. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Conventions, ILGWU: 1937-47. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Conventions, ILGWU: 1950-56. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cotton Garment and Miscellaneous Trades Department: 1934-46. Includes minutes of Hay 1946 conference. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - D: 1929, 1935-55. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Daily Worker and Morning Freiheit: 1930's. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - District Meeting, Local 22, Minutes: 1934-35. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - District Meeting, Local 22, Minutes: 1937-48 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dressmakers' Aid Committee and Credit Union: 1938-45. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Dressmakers Branch of Workmen's Circle and Dressmakers Branch 322 of International Workers Order: 1927, 1930's-50. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Dubinsky, David: 1932-38. Includes letter criticizing CSZ for taking positions contrary to Union policy re First of May demonstration, 1936. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Dubinsky, David: 1939-58. Includes CSZ letter to Dubinsky, criticizing labor's lack of support of the Free Trade Union Fund for Europe, April 1946. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - E: 1933-58. Includes letter from East Indian Railwaymen's Union on labor situation in India, 1935. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Education: 1934-58. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Education, Apparel Industry: 1936-60. Includes minutes and reports of the Educational Foundation for the Apparel Industry. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Education, Local 22: 1933-36. Includes correspondence between Mark Starr and George Simpson re Simpson's article on Local 22 in The Nation, Oct. 1935; educational programs, letters from members, printed material, reports. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Education, Local 22: 1937-38. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Education, Local 22: 1939-51. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Education, Local 22: 1952-67. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Education, Local 22, Art Shows: 1940-44. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Education, Local 22, Art Shows: 1945-56. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Education, Local 22, Dramatic Skits: 1930's-40's. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Education, Local 22, Harlem Branch: 1933-34. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Education, Local 22, Minutes and Financial Reports: 1935-36, 1942-43. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Education, Local 22, Outlines for Courses: 1934-36. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Education, Local 22, Outlines for Courses: 1937-51. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Education, National Committee for Rural Schools and United Negro College Fund: 1946-57. Includes Norman Thomas letter advising CSZ on Negro-controlled cooperative project in South Carolina, 1956. (Box 8, Folder a)
  - Educational Alliance: 1956-57. Includes correspondence and reports on program for retired members of Local 22, 1956-57. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1933. 1) Includes report of Objection and Election Committee; 2) strike of 1933 in dress industry; 3) Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union resolution to form a united front to carry on strike. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1934. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1935. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1935. Rank and File (left wing) newspaper clippings from Daily Worker and Morning Freiheit. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1936-37. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1939. Rank and File. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1940. Includes installation meeting; newspaper clippings. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1940. Progressive group. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1940. Rank and Pile. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1942. Progressive group. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1942. Rank and File. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Elections: 1944. Includes Progressive group and Rank and File group. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1944. Newspaper clippings. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - .._. Elections, Local 22: 1947. Progressive group and Rank and File group. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1947. Newspaper clippings. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1950. Progressive group and Rank and File. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1950. Newspaper clippings. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1953. Progressive group. Rank and File group and newspaper clippings. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1956. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Elections, Local 22: 1965. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Elections, Local Affiliates: 1965. Includes Local 10 and 89. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Epstein, Melech: 1951-57. Correspondence re book, Jewish Labor in USA. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - F: 1938-57. Includes Farband-Labor Zionist Order, Freedom House. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Fascism, Anti- and Anti-Nazism: 1934-43. Includes Local 22 releases, letters from Carlo Tresca. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology: 1948-56. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Federal Trade Commission: 1941. Re National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Feffer, George and Sandier, Bernie: 1942-45. Correspondence when they were in Army; Feffer paper, "Guaranteed Annual Wages in the Dress Industry," 1943. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Ferrero (Vincent) -Sallitto (Domenick) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Defense Committee: 1935-38. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Films: 1947-48. Correspondence re AFL Projects and National Film Cooperative. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Finance Committee, Local 22: 1926-36. Minutes and financial statements. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Finance Committee, Local 22: 1937-39. Minutes and financial statements. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Finance Committee, Local 22: 1940-47. Minutes, financial statements, census reports. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Font, Norma: 1954. Case. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Africa: 1943, 1956-58. Includes American Committee on Africa, Inc. South African Defense Fund and Maida Springer. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Asian Affairs: 1955-57. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Canada: 1942-55. Correspondence with Cooperative Commonwealth Federation of Canada. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Foreign Correspondence, England: 1944-53. Includes letter to Clement R. Attlee and Ernest Bevin, criticizing (British Labour) government on treatment of Jews in Palestine, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Foreign Correspondence, France: 1945-54. Includes correspondence with Irving Brown (AFL rep. in Europe) and F. Shrager on Communist activities in Europe. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Foreign Correspondence, France: 1950, 1958-69. Unser Stimme. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Germany: 1933-45. Includes correspondence re relief to victims of Nazism, trade union movement and post-war reconstruction, especially German trade union movement. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Germany: 1946-53. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Hungary: 1956. Re Hungarian revolution. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Correspondence, India: 1934, 1948-58. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Poland: 1936-47. Includes correspondence on aiding Polish-Jews. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Russia: 1933-45. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Russia: 1946-70. Includes Raphael Abramovitch outline report on History of Russian Revolution Project, 1957; CSZ statement at Jewish Labor Committee meeting re Russian anti-Semitism, 1966. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Correspondence, South America: 1950, 1954-55. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Spain: 1935-40. Includes correspondence with and reports from Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; New World Resettlement Fund, Inc., and other organizations on Spanish Refugee Aid during and after Civil War. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Spain: 1941-46, 1952-58. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Springer, Maida: 1945-62. Includes correspondence, reports on trade union activities in Africa; her European and USA (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - activities, 1945-55; AFL-CIO and ILGWU garment worker program, 1960-62. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Correspondence, Miscellaneous Countries: 1941, 1944-61. Includes China, Cuba, Norway, Denmark and Sweden; study by Abe S. Weiss, Garment Workers of Other Lands, 1941. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Forest Neighborhood House, Inc.: 1946-58. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Form Letters: 1933-47. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Forward, Jewish Daily: 1934-56. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Free Trade Union Committee: 1947-56. Includes Jay Lovestone reports; Irving Brown report on trade union activities in Europe, 1947; Maida Springer report on Africa, 1952. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Freeland League: 1946-49. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Friedman, David: 1940-52. Newspaper clipping articles in Morning Freiheit. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - G: 1937-49. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Gaskin, Lillian W.: 1933-36. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - General Executive Board: 1934-58. Includes Isidore Nagler report to GEB on overlapping problem between cloak and dress industry, 1938; CSZ report on trip to European countries for Jewish Labor Committee, 1946; CSZ memorandum on Latin America as an export market. May 1946. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Gerjoy, Ben, and Lipnack, Sol: 1939. Statements from Local 22 and newspaper clippings on their expulsion from Communist Party. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Greetings and Condolences: 1934-57. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Grievance Committee: 1933-37. Cases. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Grievance Committee: 1938-41. Cases. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Grievance Committee: 1942-51. Cases. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Grievance Committee: 1933, 1951, 1952-54. Max Goldberg case, 1933; Sam Peltz case, 1941; Hilda Tormay case, 1952-54. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Gross, Murray: 1943-45. Correspondence with Gross in Army. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - H: 1935-58. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Haber, S. 1943-53. Newspaper articles in Morning Freiheit. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Harlem Section Dressmakers: 1930's. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Harvard University: 1946-48. Includes correspondence with Walter Galenson and Irving Brown on European situation and aid to Norwegian Labor Party. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Health, Committee for the Nation's: 1952-55. (Box 14, Folder 6)